Guide to the William Darlington Papers 1800-1863 MS 1165
New-York Historical Society
William Darlington papers
1800-1863
New-York Historical Society
Darlington, William, 1782-1863
MS 1165
4.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, scrapbooks, a ship's log, and a minute book of William Darlington (1782-1863). Collection includes correspondence with botanists, physicians, scientists, scholars, political and public figures, publishers, business acquaintances, museum officials, friends, and family (10 v. in 8 boxes). Diaries cover his time in medical school, various trips through Pennsylvania, and the period 1815-1821 during which he was a congressman. Other volumes include a history of the Tullian Society of Philadelphia, log of the ship "Bengal" on a voyage from Calcutta toward Philadelphia, two scrapbooks of newspaper clippings pertaining to current events, items of interest, and history of the Revolutionary War, a book of various types of songs written by Darlington, some autobiographical material, and a book of minutes of the commissioners appointed to lay out a state road from New Hope to the state line toward Baltimore. Frequent correspondents include: Spencer F. Baird, Isabella Batchelder, Wm. Arnold Bromfield, Anna Maria Collinson, Moses A. Curtis, B.S. Barton Darlington, William B. Darlington, John Ward Dean, W.H. Dillingham, Eliza Fell, Asa Gray, Thomas P. James, Benson J. Lossing, Elizabeth C. Morris, Dr. Ezra Michener, George F. Randolph, Lewis D. v. Schweinitz, C.W. Short, and John Torrey.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in two series:
Series I. Correspondence, circa 1800-1863
Series II. Diaries and Scrapbooks, 1804-1863, undated
The arrangement of Series I was established at an earlier date. An index to the correspondence has been reproduced here in full. Series II has been arranged chronologically.
Biographical note
William Darlington was a physician, botanist, and member of the U.S. House of Representatives. He was born in Birmingham, Chester County, Pennsylvania on April 28, 1782 and received a medical degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1804. He served as a surgeon on a merchant ship in 1807, and upon his return, settled in West Chester, Pennsylvania. At the beginning of the War of 1812, he raised a company of volunteers and later served as a major. Darlington was a Republican member of the House of Representatives from 1815-1817 and 1819-1923. In 1825, Darlington was appointed to the State Canal Commission, and in 1830, he served on the State Road Commission. Darlington stablished a natural history society in West Chester in 1826 and published several books on botany, including Agricultural Botany (1847) and Flora Cestrica (1853). From 1830-1863, Darlington served as the director and president of the National Bank of Chester County. He died in West Chester, Pennsylvania on April 23, 1863.
[This note is drawn from Darlington's entry in the Biographical Directory of the United States Senate: https://bioguide.congress.gov/search/bio/D000059]
Related Materials
For related material, please see AHMC Darlington.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence written and received by Darlington and his contemporaries. Included are letters from physicians, scientists, scholars, political figures, publishers, business acquaintances, and family members. There are a number of letters from prominent 19th century botanists, including John Torrey, Charles Short, Ezra Michener, Moses A. Curtis, John C. Porter, William Bromfield, Elizabeth C. Morris, Anna Maria Collinson, and J.W. Phelps. The 1859 letters from J.W. Phelps describe pottery shards and hieroglyphics found in the Great Basin region of Utah. Other letters from Phelps describe the landscape surrounding the military post of Fort Brown, Texas. Another botanist, Miles Rock, sent Darlington descriptions of local flora from the Civil War battlefields of Bull Run in Virginia.
Additional correspondence includes personal letters from Darlington sons. Darlington's diaries cover his time in medical school; various trips through Pennsylvania; and his service in Congress, including detailed notes on the Missouri Compromise and ballot counts for presidential elections. Other volumes include a history of the Tullian Society of Philadelphia; a ship logbook; scrapbooks; and minutes from the State Road Commission.
Pennsylvania -- Social life and customs -- 19th century.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States -- Politics and government -- 19th century.; Botany; Medicine -- Study and teaching; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Scrapbooks.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1800-1863
  - Allen, F.A. & C.H. (Volume 1, Item 495A)
  - Allibone, S. Austin (Volume 1, Item 486)
  - Armstrong, Edward (Volume 1, Item 220/221)
  - Atkins, Layton Y. (Volume 1, Item 355/355A)
  - Atlee, John L. (Volume 1, Item 183)
  - Auld, E.A. (Volume 1, Item 166)
  - Baily, William L. (Volume 1, Item 297)
  - Baird, Spencer F. (Volume 1, Item 72, 73, 74, 76, 78, 84, 85, 92, 105, 116, 121, 130, 176, 177, 178, 186, 195, 196, 200, 306, 320, 325, 326, 327, 479)
  - Balch, Rev. Dr. Lewis (Volume 1, Item 145, 148, 237, 477, 483)
  - Barnard, T.D. (Volume 1, Item 189)
  - Bartram, John (Volume 1, Item 81)
  - Batchelder, Samuel (Volume 1, Item 214)
  - Bateham, M.B. (Volume 1, Item 108, 151, 157, 159)
  - Bettle, Samuel, Jr. (Volume 1, Item 290)
  - Blodget, Lorin (Volume 1, Item 244, 295, 296)
  - Brewer, William H. (Volume 1, Item 257, 258)
  - Broomall, Nathan G. (Volume 1, Item 184)
  - Browne, Peter A. (Volume 1, Item 292, 293)
  - Childs, George W. (Volume 1, Item 338)
  - Clark, Henry (Volume 1, Item 505)
  - Cooper, S. (Volume 1, Item 191)
  - Cope, Caleb (Volume 1, Item 165)
  - Cunard, E. (Volume 1, Item 275, 285, 286, 300)
  - Curtis, Jared (Volume 1, Item 487)
  - Curtis, Moses A., Rev. (Volume 1, Item 488)
  - Daingerfield, William Henry (Volume 1, Item 111-113)
  - Darlington, Edward C. (Volume 1, Item 144, 146, 294)
  - Darlington, Fenelon (Volume 1, Item 119, 152)
  - Darlington, William (Volume 1, Item 149, 150, 243, 248)
  - Darlington, William (of Stephen) (Volume 1, Item 147, 212-213)
  - Darlington, William B. (Volume 1, Item 223, 273, 501-503)
  - Davies, Charles (Volume 1, Item 201)
  - Davis, W.W.H. (Volume 1, Item 168-174, 181-182, 197, 199, 238)
  - Dean, John Ward (Volume 1, Item 358-362, 364-365, 466-468A)
  - Deoneux & Company (Volume 1, Item 500)
  - Derrick, A.H. (Volume 1, Item 192)
  - Dillingham, C.C. (Volume 1, Item 224-225)
  - Doran, T.A., Dr. (Volume 1, Item 356)
  - Draper, Lyman C. (Volume 1, Item 246, 255, 311)
  - DuBois, C. (Volume 1, Item 242)
  - Durand, E. (Volume 1, Item 240, 328)
  - Durnal, Milton (Volume 1, Item 185)
  - Elliott, Stephen, Bishop (Volume 1, Item 267)
  - Elliott, Washington L., Capt. (Volume 1, Item 235)
  - Ellis, Y.B. (Volume 1, Item 222)
  - Emerson, George B. (Volume 1, Item 47)
  - English, Thomas Dunn (Volume 1, Item 156)
  - Ennis, J. (Volume 1, Item 504)
  - Everhart, William (Volume 1, Item 188)
  - Flanner, Henry Beeson (Volume 1, Item 331, 332, 333, 334-337, 341-343, 509)
  - Flanner, Orpha Annette (Volume 1, Item 331, 332, 333)
  - Foreman, E. (Volume 1, Item 120)
  - Fraley, F. (Volume 1, Item 303/304)
  - French, B.V. (Volume 1, Item 478)
  - Frost, Charles C. (Volume 1, Item 241)
  - Futhey, R.A. (Volume 1, Item 266, 287)
  - Gibbons, Henry (Volume 1, Item 251)
  - Gibbons, James S. (Volume 1, Item 138, 142-143, 164, 288)
  - Gilbert, Howard Worcester (Volume 1, Item 260, 265, 268)
  - Gilpin, Thomas (Volume 1, Item 48, 52, 64, 67)
  - Gray, Asa, Dr. (Volume 1, Item 5-31, 33-46, 49, 51, 54-59, 61-63, 68-70, 86-89, 94-99, 117, 131, 134, 140, 141, 179-180, 183/184, 198, 202/203-206, 208-211, 308/309, 314, 322, 329, 469, 4772-472A, 474-475, 492-494A)
  - Greenwood, G.G.B. (Volume 1, Item 239)
  - Hanson, Hugh Cooper (Volume 1, Item 190, 270, 271, 272, 274, 277-279)
  - Hayden, S. (Volume 1, Item 496, 499)
  - Hazard, Samuel (Volume 1, Item 136, 140A)
  - Henry, Joseph (Volume 1, Item 77, 104, 114, 133, 139, 175, 207, 307, 317, 319, 321)
  - Higgins, P.S. (Volume 1, Item 167)
  - Hopkins, M. (Volume 1, Item 252)
  - Howard, Sanford (Volume 1, Item 219)
  - Hunt, Uriah & Son (Volume 1, Item 264)
  - Husted, William V. (Volume 1, Item 490)
  - Ivision (of Ivision & Phinney) (Volume 1, Item 312)
  - Jackson, William (Volume 1, Item 154)
  - James, Thomas P. (Volume 1, Item 50, 60,65, 75, 82, 83, 91, 93, 100-103, 122-129, 313, 315, 323-324, 481)
  - Jones, Griffith (Volume 1, Item 218)
  - Jordan, John, Jr. (Volume 1, Item 353, 480, 491)
  - Kettering, Valentine (Volume 1, Item 4)
  - Lacy, H (Volume 1, Item 155)
  - "Latin Salutatory" (Volume 1, Item 259)
  - Lewis, Charlton (Volume 1, Item 71)
  - Lewis, James J. (Volume 1, Item 261, 354)
  - Lewis, Samuel (Volume 1, Item 330)
  - Maris, Jesse J. (Volume 1, Item 153, 158)
  - M'Clune, James (Volume 1, Item 137)
  - McMichael, J. (Volume 1, Item 302)
  - Meehan, Thomas (Volume 1, Item 160, 161, 484)
  - Mendenhall, J.D. (Volume 1, Item 473)
  - Michener, Ezra, Dr. (Volume 1, Item 496A)
  - Missing (Volume 1, Item 32, 363, 366-465)
  - Morris, Anthony (Volume 1, Item 298, 299)
  - Newton, Richard, Rev. (Volume 1, Item 305, 310)
  - Newton, William (Volume 1, Item 495)
  - Norris, George W. (Volume 1, Item 289)
  - Pearce, George W. (Volume 1, Item 135, 291)
  - Pearson, Sarah Y.H. (cousin) (Volume 1, Item 249A)
  - Phelps, J.W., Capt. (Volume 1, Item 497, 498, 507/508)
  - Pollock, John B. (Volume 1, Item 132)
  - Potter, Bishop Alonzo (Volume 1, Item 247)
  - Price, Eli K. (Volume 1, Item 262)
  - Ray, William Porter (Volume 1, Item 245)
  - Reichert, Jean (Volume 1, Item 3)
  - Roberts, Edward P. (Volume 1, Item 79, 80)
  - Roset (of Roset & Troutman) (Volume 1, Item 115, 118, 187, 256)
  - Roset, John (Volume 1, Item 276)
  - Sargent, N. (Volume 1, Item 250)
  - Seal, Thomas F. (Volume 1, Item 90, 107)
  - Short, C.W. (Volume 1, Item 485, 489)
  - Small, G.H. (Volume 1, Item 263)
  - Smith, Daniel B. (Volume 1, Item 344, 345)
  - Smith, John Jay (Volume 1, Item 66, 280-284, 318-318A, 339-340)
  - Spangler, A.M. (Volume 1, Item 253)
  - Stauffer, J. (Volume 1, Item 269)
  - Stoever, M.D. (Volume 1, Item 106)
  - Table of Contents (Volume 1, Item 1,2)
  - Tatnall, Edward, Jr. (Volume 1, Item 163, 216)
  - Thomas, Richard M. (Volume 1, Item 357)
  - Thurber, George (Volume 1, Item 471, 476, 482)
  - Townsend, Henry C. (Volume 1, Item 254)
  - Townsend, Washington (Volume 1, Item 215)
  - Townshend, Norton S. (Volume 1, Item 301)
  - Treadwell, Robert O. (Volume 1, Item 109, 110)
  - Troutman (of Roset & Troutman) (Volume 1, Item 115, 118, 187, 256)
  - Tweddle, John (Volume 1, Item 226, 249)
  - Vermont State Historical-Antiquarian Society (Volume 1, Item 506)
  - Ward, James W. (Volume 1, Item 162)
  - Ward, Townsend (Pennsylvania Historical Society) (Volume 1, Item 346-349)
  - Watson, John (Volume 1, Item 53)
  - Willis, Oliver R. (Volume 1, Item 350/351, 352)
  - Wilson, William C. (Volume 1, Item 229/230-234, 236)
  - Wyers, William F. (Volume 1, Item 217, 227, 228)
  - Adams, John Quincy (Volume 2, Item 37)
  - Agardh, James G. (Volume 2, Item 107/107A, 108)
  - Agassiz, L (Volume 2, Item 139, 140)
  - Alexander, R.C. (Volume 2, Item 131)
  - American Linnean Society (Volume 2, Item 151)
  - American Philosophical Society (Volume 2, Item 157, 165, 198, 202)
  - Anthon, Charles (Volume 2, Item 120)
  - Anthony, John G. (Volume 2, Item 216)
  - Association of American Geologists (Volume 2, Item 204, 208)
  - Ayres, W.O. (Volume 2, Item 251)
  - Bache, A.D. (Volume 2, Item 126)
  - Baird, Spencer F. (Volume 2, Item 122)
  - Barton, Benjamin Smith (Volume 2, Item 12, 13)
  - Barton, W. (Volume 2, Item 16, 17, 18, 19)
  - Beekman, J.P. (Volume 2, Item 179)
  - Bentham, George (Volume 2, Item 133)
  - Biddle, Thomas (Volume 2, Item 23)
  - Bigelow, J. (Volume 2, Item 27)
  - Boott, F., Dr. (Volume 2, Item 74-84)
  - Brace, John P. (Volume 2, Item 73)
  - Brakeley, John H. (Volume 2, Item 197)
  - Breck, Samuel (Volume 2, Item 130)
  - Brickenstein, Herman (Volume 2, Item 259)
  - Bryant, Cyrus (Volume 2, Item 175)
  - Bulletin for Natural Sciences (Volume 2, Item 174)
  - Calhoun, J.C. (Volume 2, Item 24, 25, 26)
  - Cass, Lewis (Volume 2, Item 106)
  - Chester County Medical Society (Volume 2, Item 239)
  - Chrismon, John B. (Volume 2, Item 181)
  - Cincinnati Historical Society (Volume 2, Item 209)
  - Circular-State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Volume 2, Item 249)
  - Combe, George (Volume 2, Item 113)
  - Cooper, William (Volume 2, Item 61-66)
  - Cosson, E. (Volume 2, Item 118)
  - Coxe, John Redman (Volume 2, Item 14, 15)
  - Dana, James D. (Volume 2, Item 146)
  - Darlington, William (Volume 2, Item 44A, 153, 164, 166A, 168, 170, 227, 229)
  - DeJussieu, Adrien (Volume 2, Item 135)
  - Delaware College (Volume 2, Item 222, 223, 224)
  - Delaware County Institute of Science (Volume 2, Item 232)
  - Derrick, A.H. (Volume 2, Item 192)
  - Desha, Joseph, Gen. (Volume 2, Item 20)
  - DeVriese, W.H. (Volume 2, Item 137A)
  - Dickerson, M. (Volume 2, Item 111)
  - Dickeson, M.W. (Volume 2, Item 219)
  - Dickins, Asbury (Volume 2, Item 155)
  - Dougherty, Thomas (Volume 2, Item 34)
  - Douglass, D.B. (Volume 2, Item 58)
  - Draper, Lyman C. (Volume 2, Item 248)
  - Ducatel, J.T. (Volume 2, Item 176)
  - Dunglison, R., Prof. (Volume 2, Item 145)
  - Eaton, Amos (Volume 2, Item 68-70)
  - Eleazer, A.L. (Volume 2, Item 129)
  - Finch, John (Volume 2, Item 50, 51)
  - Findlay, William (Volume 2, Item 28)
  - Fischer, Prof. (Volume 2, Item 97-101)
  - French Institute - Royal Academy of Science (Volume 2, Item 191)
  - Gemmil, John, Rev. (Volume 2, Item 4)
  - General Lafayette's Reply (Volume 2, Item 46)
  - Germain, Ernest (Volume 2, Item 118)
  - Gibson, George S. (Volume 2, Item 177)
  - Gould, Augustus A. (Volume 2, Item 201)
  - Graham, George, Jr. (Volume 2, Item 180)
  - Graham, W.S.T. (Volume 2, Item 220)
  - Haines, Reuben (Volume 2, Item 154)
  - Hardy, Charles O. (Volume 2, Item 186)
  - Hare, Robert (Volume 2, Item 132)
  - Harvard College (Volume 2, Item 184, 195, 199, 233)
  - Hayes, Isaac J. (Volume 2, Item 149)
  - Henderson, R.A. (Volume 2, Item 169, 171-173)
  - Henry, Joseph (Volume 2, Item 141-142)
  - Herrick, Edward C. (Volume 2, Item 246, 256)
  - Hewson, Thomas T., Dr. (Volume 2, Item 29)
  - Hiester, Isaac (Volume 2, Item 109)
  - Hiester, Joseph (Governor of Pennsylvania) (Volume 2, Item 35, 36)
  - Historical Society of Pennsylvania (Volume 2, Item 205)
  - Hooker, W.J., Prof. (Volume 2, Item 84A-96)
  - Horticultural Society of Pennsylvania (Volume 2, Item 200)
  - Huebener, L.R. (Volume 2, Item 254A, 258A)
  - Jewett, C.C. (Volume 2, Item 230-231, 235, 237-238)
  - Johnson, R.M. (Volume 2, Item 49)
  - Jordan, John, Jr. (Volume 2, Item 206-207)
  - Kennedy, Eugene A. (Volume 2, Item 228)
  - Lancaster, Joseph (Volume 2, Item 30, 31, 32/33)
  - Lenox, D. (Volume 2, Item 22)
  - Lewisburg Lyceum (Volume 2, Item 190)
  - Leyden Botonical Society (Volume 2, Item 254)
  - Library Company of Philadelphia (Volume 2, Item 236)
  - Logan Institute (Volume 2, Item 242)
  - Lossing, Benson J. (Volume 2, Item 147)
  - Lyceum of Natural History (Volume 2, Item 167)
  - Markoe, Francis, Jr. (Volume 2, Item 193, 194)
  - Martins, Charles (Volume 2, Item 102-105)
  - McClure, Charles (Volume 2, Item 125)
  - Meehan, John S. (Volume 2, Item 203, 218)
  - Meigs, J. (Librarian - Tennessee Historical Society) (Volume 2, Item 260)
  - Milnor, John P. (Volume 2, Item 160)
  - Missing (Volume 2, Item 56, 71)
  - Mitchell, J. (Pennsylvania Horticultural Society) (Volume 2, Item 241)
  - Moravian Historical Society (Volume 2, Item 254A, 258A, 259)
  - Muhlenberg, F.A., Dr. (Volume 2, Item 134)
  - Muller, J. Christopher (Volume 2, Item 59, 60)
  - Museum of Natural History - Paris (Volume 2, Item 182)
  - National Institute for the Promotion of Science (Volume 2, Item 196)
  - Natural History Society - Yale College (Volume 2, Item 187)
  - New England Historic-Genealogical Society (Volume 2, Item 257, 258)
  - New Orleans Medical Society (Volume 2, Item 156)
  - Onderdonk, Henry U. (Volume 2, Item 114-116)
  - Oxford Agricultural Committee (Volume 2, Item 215)
  - Parker, Alvin H. (Volume 2, Item 183)
  - Penn, Granoille John (Volume 2, Item 148)
  - Pennsylvania Society of Cincinnati (Volume 2, Item 21)
  - Percival, Thomas C. (Volume 2, Item 217)
  - Peters, Richard (Volume 2, Item 38)
  - Philadelphia Agricultural Society (Volume 2, Item 189)
  - Philadelphia Botanical Society - Palmer, Thomas H. (Volume 2, Item 152)
  - Pickering, Charles (Volume 2, Item 123, 124)
  - Potter, Bishop Alonzo (Volume 2, Item 127-128A)
  - Powell, John Hare (Volume 2, Item 162/163)
  - Price, Jacob (Volume 2, Item 245)
  - Pyle, Isaac D. (Volume 2, Item 214)
  - Quincy, Josiah (Volume 2, Item 184, 195, 199)
  - Randall, A. (Volume 2, Item 210-213)
  - Reed, Joseph (Volume 2, Item 47)
  - Rich, William (Volume 2, Item 67)
  - Riddell, Samuel H. (Volume 2, Item 257)
  - Roberts, Jonathan (Volume 2, Item 119)
  - Rogers, Henry D. (Volume 2, Item 110)
  - Root, Erastus (Volume 2, Item 117)
  - Rush, Benjamin, Dr. (Volume 2, Item 1,3)
  - Rush, Richard (Volume 2, Item 42)
  - Rush, Samuel (Volume 2, Item 2)
  - Sergeant, John (Volume 2, Item 48)
  - Sergeant, Thomas (President - Historical Society of Pennsylvania) (Volume 2, Item 205)
  - Shepard, Charles Upham (Volume 2, Item 204)
  - Shulze, J. Andrew (Governor of Pennsylvania) (Volume 2, Item 45)
  - Shunk, F.R. (Volume 2, Item 44)
  - Silliman, B., Prof. (Volume 2, Item 39, 40/41, 43, 121, 144, 188)
  - Silliman, Benjamin, Dr. (Volume 2, Item 188)
  - Simmons, John (Volume 2, Item 185)
  - Smith, Daniel B. (Volume 2, Item 52, 53)
  - Smith, John B. (Volume 2, Item 200)
  - Smith, Lloyd P. (Volume 2, Item 252, 236)
  - Sparks, Jared (Volume 2, Item 233)
  - Steinhauer, D. (Volume 2, Item 72)
  - Stewart, Com. (Volume 2, Item 138)
  - Streeter, S.V. (Volume 2, Item 150)
  - Tatnall, Edward, Jr. (Volume 2, Item 234)
  - Tennessee Historical Society (Volume 2, Item 260)
  - Thomson, Charles (Volume 2, Item 5)
  - Tiffany, O.H. (Volume 2, Item 250)
  - Tilton,James, Dr. (Volume 2, Item 40734)
  - Trumbull, John (Volume 2, Item 6)
  - Turnpenny, Joseph C. (Volume 2, Item 244)
  - Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah (Volume 2, Item 55, 57)
  - Vaughan, John (Volume 2, Item 158/159)
  - Wade, Benjamin Franklin, Hon. (Volume 2, Item 143)
  - Walker, Robert C. (Volume 2, Item 240)
  - Wallace, D.C. (Volume 2, Item 178)
  - Walsh, Robert (Volume 2, Item 54)
  - Ward, Townsend (Pennsylvania Historical Society) (Volume 2, Item 243, 247, 253)
  - Weaver, H.W. (Volume 2, Item 255)
  - Webster, Noah (Volume 2, Item 112)
  - West Point Lyceum (Volume 2, Item 164)
  - Wharton, T.J. (Volume 2, Item 161)
  - Wils, Bourse, Dr. (Volume 2, Item 136, 137)
  - Wilson, James P., Rev. (Volume 2, Item 221)
  - Woolsey, Theodore D. (President - Yale College) (Volume 2, Item 225, 226)
  - Yale College (Volume 2, Item 225, 226)
  - Yale Natural History Society (Volume 2, Item 187)
  - "Song" (Volume 3, Item 71)
  - Allen, Nathan (Volume 3, Item 107)
  - Allibone, S. Austin (Volume 3, Item 117)
  - Bache, Franklin (Volume 3, Item 104)
  - Bache, Thomas Hewson, Dr. (Volume 3, Item 142, 143, 144)
  - Bacon, Francis D. (Volume 3, Item 102)
  - Barker, J.N. (Volume 3, Item 44)
  - Barnard, J.D. (Volume 3, Item 59, 60, 61-65, 67, 68)
  - Bentley, John P. (Volume 3, Item 111)
  - Blackie, George S. (Volume 3, Item 132, 133)
  - Boileau, N.B. (Volume 3, Item 34A)
  - Bringhurst, D. (Volume 3, Item 19)
  - Bringhurst, D. & Joseph (Volume 3, Item 15)
  - Bringhurst, Joseph (Volume 3, Item 16, 17, 18)
  - Burroughs, Charles (Volume 3, Item 114)
  - Butand, J. (Volume 3, Item 36)
  - Canal Commissioners - Duties 1827 (Volume 3, Item 90)
  - Canby, James (Volume 3, Item 37)
  - Chambers, David (Volume 3, Item 88)
  - Chew, B. (Volume 3, Item 85)
  - Coates, B.H. (Volume 3, Item 109)
  - Coleman, Daniel (Volume 3, Item 27A, 57)
  - Collins, Laccheus (Volume 3, Item 84)
  - Conyell, Lewis S. (Volume 3, Item 86)
  - Cook, Charles (Volume 3, Item 121)
  - Cope, Alfred (Volume 3, Item 129, 130, 131)
  - Coppee, H., Prof. (Volume 3, Item 134)
  - Darlington, B.S. Barton (Volume 3, Item 151-152, 154, 156-157, 159-160, 162, 164-166, 169, 171-177, 178A-179A, 181-182, 184-188, 193-197, 198-207, 210, 212-267, 280-288)
  - Darlington, Edward (Volume 3, Item 6, 268-269)
  - Darlington, Hannah (Volume 3, Item 5A)
  - Darlington, Isaac (Volume 3, Item 69-70)
  - Darlington, J. & C.L. (Volume 3, Item 168)
  - Darlington, John Lacey (Volume 3, Item 46-50, 167, 189)
  - Darlington, L. (Volume 3, Item 76)
  - Darlington, William (Volume 3, Item 5, 7, 20-23, 43, 56, 79, 92-93, 97, 103A, 153, 155, 158, 161, 163, 170, 178, 180, 183, 190-191, 208-209)
  - Dean, John Ward (Volume 3, Item 135-137)
  - Delavan, Benjamin, Dr. (Volume 3, Item 45)
  - DeRham, H.C. (Volume 3, Item 74, 75)
  - Dillard, Thomas (Volume 3, Item 289)
  - Duane, William (Volume 3, Item 33)
  - Dulany, D. French (Volume 3, Item 289A)
  - Elwyn, Alfred Langdon (Volume 3, Item 141)
  - French, B.V. (Volume 3, Item 115)
  - Furness, W.H., Rev. (Volume 3, Item 105)
  - Gadsden, Colonel (Volume 3, Item 72)
  - Garnett, James (Volume 3, Item 108)
  - Gemmil, Rebecca (Volume 3, Item 55)
  - Gibbons, Henry (Volume 3, Item 113)
  - Gibson,W., Prof. (Volume 3, Item 83)
  - Gilpin, Henry D. (Volume 3, Item 127)
  - Gold, William Henry (Volume 3, Item 112)
  - Good, Jesse (Volume 3, Item 73)
  - Griffin, William Preston (Volume 3, Item 290)
  - Harland, Richard (Volume 3, Item 96)
  - Hazard, Samuel (Volume 3, Item 128)
  - Hibler, Jacob (Volume 3, Item 118)
  - Hiester, D. (Volume 3, Item 34)
  - James, Thomas P. (Volume 3, Item 80)
  - Jones, R. (Volume 3, Item 110)
  - Jordan, John, Jr. (Volume 3, Item 146-147)
  - Kemper, Reuben (Volume 3, Item 40, 41)
  - Kenny, Charles (Volume 3, Item 39, 51)
  - Kinnard, Andrew (Volume 3, Item 89)
  - Lacey, A. (Volume 3, Item 27)
  - Lacey, Charles (Volume 3, Item 54)
  - Lacey, J. (Volume 3, Item 25, 26, 27, 28-31)
  - Lacey, Thomas R. (Volume 3, Item 32)
  - Lanman, Charles (Volume 3, Item 150)
  - Leib, John L. (Volume 3, Item 35)
  - Lewis, William D. (Volume 3, Item 122, 123)
  - Lossing, Benson J. (Volume 3, Item 116)
  - Luna, Antonio (Volume 3, Item 99)
  - McIlvaine, Joseph (Volume 3, Item 94)
  - M'Clellan, Joseph (Volume 3, Item 34)
  - Missing (Volume 3, Item 192)
  - Morgan, Mordelai (Volume 3, Item 53)
  - Mother of B.S.B. Darlington (Volume 3, Item 197A)
  - Painter, Sarah D. (Volume 3, Item 52)
  - Pass, The (Volume 3, Item 211)
  - Patterson, Robert (Volume 3, Item 87)
  - Pearce, C., Colonel (Volume 3, Item 42)
  - Pearce, Joseph (Volume 3, Item 77)
  - Pennock, Caspar W. (Volume 3, Item 139, 140)
  - Poole, William (Volume 3, Item 38)
  - Prince, Wlliam (Volume 3, Item 95)
  - Pugh, Evan (Volume 3, Item 119, 120)
  - Read, Sam J. (Volume 3, Item 24)
  - Reed, Joseph (Volume 3, Item 82)
  - Rich, William (Volume 3, Item 66)
  - Roberdeau, Major (Volume 3, Item 78)
  - Roche, Charles, Mons. (Volume 3, Item 11)
  - Rogers, Charles (Volume 3, Item 34)
  - Service, Hugh, Dr. (Volume 3, Item 40890)
  - Shippen, George D. (Volume 3, Item 138)
  - Shunk, F.R. (Volume 3, Item 91)
  - Smith, Thomas Lacey (Volume 3, Item 81)
  - Southwick, S. (Volume 3, Item 58)
  - Stevens, William A., Rev. (Volume 3, Item 98)
  - Thomas, David (Volume 3, Item 100, 101)
  - Thompson, B. (Volume 3, Item 40764)
  - Trist, N.P. (Volume 3, Item 124-126A)
  - Van Armringe, H.H. (Volume 3, Item 103)